Vishrut Singhal

Senior Software Test Engineer

Noida | 9560607194/7906626400 | vishrutsinghal261@gmail.com

Work History

Senior Software Test Engineer

2017-11 - Still

Xavient Information System

TELUS International (CANADA) 2017-11- Still

(Telecom Domain)

TELUS International is a subsidiary of TELUS, a national telecommunications company in Canada. TELUS International provides global contact center outsourcing, business process outsourcing, and IT outsourcing services

Responsibilities:

Leading Team of 4 employees.

Indulge in certain client POC for automation frameworks.

 $\label{thm:condition} Creation of High level scenarios from the FRDs Test case creation from the high level scenarios.$

Indulge in core Python development.

Maintenance and creation of the Automation framework(Hybrid and ATDD) and writing scripts in seleniumJava.

Developed Key Based driven based framework in python in Robot framework.

Technology:

Functional Testing, DataBase Testing(SQL), Automation Testing, Python DEv.

Tools:

HP-ALM, Jenkins, SQL-Server, JIRA

Senior Software Engineer(NIIT TECHNOLOGIES)

2016-01 - 2017-10

(Banking Domain)

SEI(U.S.)

SEI(NASDAQ: SEIC) is a leading global provider of asset management, investment processing, and investment operations solutions for institutional and personal wealth management.

SEI is a global provider of investment processing, investment management, and investment operations solutions. SEI provides products and services to corporations, financial institutions, financial advisors, and ultra-high-wealth individuals.

Responsibilities:

Creation of High level scenarios from the FRDs Test case creation from the high level scenarios.

Script creation and maintenancein Selenium BDD framework.

Created custom libraries for framework(Excel reader, properties)

Integration of the selenium framework with JENKINS.

Peer reviews of the test Scenarios/Cases.

Execution of test scripts in TFS Defect logging in TFS Defect revalidation and re execution of test cases

Oracle DB testing, data validation from back end to data in reports generated in the course of the data extraction and production support.

Technology:

Manual Testing,, DataBase Testing(PL/SQL) Tools: Oracle 10g, TFS, JIRA

Software Engineer
OPTIMA TESTING (Airline Domain)

2014-11 - 2015-11

Skills

IT Skills

Selenium (java/python) automation testing

SQL Database Testing

Python scripting

Manual Testing

Functional Testing

Regression Testing

Database Testing

Selenium Grid

PyWin(Python)

Robot Framework - Selenium(Python)

Python Kivy.

Summary

4.2 years of experience in software testing.

Well versed with all stages of Software Testing life and good hands on

Functional Testing, Regression testing, Database Testing. Good Exposure of Bug Life cycle.

Testing Experience in Database Testing (PL/SQL).

- Worked for both Development and Maintenance software projects.
- Developing and maintaining Automation frameworks.
- •Developed Key Based driven based framework in python in Robot framework.
- Indulging in maintenance in selenium based framework (Hybrid Framework)
- Domains: Insurance, Airline (Cargo), Banking, Telecom.

Out Of Box

 Created a python tool "Advance Search" which generates a path and fetch(opens) the file from the selected location. (BA-D4K UK) From as Software Engineer(Manual Testing) Optima 2C is a billing/Revenue management system for IAG(BA and IB), which is being used For Cargo reservation and billing by both the Airlines.

The project includes integration between The IB billing system(AVCD) and the BA billing system(BA80) along with Optima, which is a web, based application integrated with these two systems.

Responsibilities:

Creation of High level scenarios from the FRDs.

Test case creation from the high level scenarios. Peer reviews of the test Scenarios/Cases.

Involved in creation of the scripts for web based application in selenium framework.

Execution of test scripts in HP ALM. Regression testing of the E2E system.

Defect revalidation and re execution of test cases.

Technology: Manual Testing Tools: Quality Center(HP), Selenium

Associate Software Engineer

2014-01 - 2014-10

Bankers Insurance Group(U.S.) (Insurance)

From as Associate Software Engineer(Developer and Manual and Automation Tester). Bankers Insurance Group is U. S based company which deals in Insurance Domain despite its name. My team consists 12 members including me.

Responsibilities

Involved in all the phases of SDLC.

Ability to analyze requirements, understands high level logic of programs, find and fix the bugs.

Good analytical, communication, both written and verbal, and presentation skills.

Review the test cases/plans, deliverables and implement changes, including staging and production environment moves.

Coordinating with QA team during new releases into production.

Participated in initiatives regarding the improvement of quality of the deliverables within the tea Perform Regression testing for the required data cases created.

Front and Backend Testing including creating scenarios in both the environment for testing. Production Check for daily submission of job and policies creation.

Technology: AS400, Testing, Regression Testing, Automation Testing. Tools: Soap UI, Selenium.

Education

Intermediate 2008 - 2009

St Mary's senior secondary school

75%, (ICSE)

Bachelor's in Technology

2009-08 - 2013

Uttar Pradesh Technical University

71.8%, (Meerut Institute of Engineering and Technology)

Key Features of the tool

- It will generates a path from root directory (drive)
- It will automatically open the file from the location, if multiple paths are there for similar file, tool will append the file at run time and opens the file for different locations.
- It will unzip the zip or .tar file and opens the file in the zip folder.
- If multiple paths were found it will prompt the user to choose the path.

Personal Details

Passport and Visa Details: Passport Status: Ready

Personal Details Born on 26/05/1991, Single

Contact Information Address: F-44, sector 41, Noida Mobile No.: 9560607194/7906626400 Email Id:vishrutsinghal261@gmail.com